Gheorghe Despina

EDS Engineer

gigidespina@gmail.com

Summary

I am working as an electrical engineer since April 2008,

I had worked on different kind of projects like:

- Enel projects, where I used ABB primary and secondary equipment for power stations,
- CEZ projects, where I used SIEMENS primary and secondary equipments for power stations,
- URS projects, like FGD projects and Oil&Gas projects.

From 2013, I joined Renault as Engine harness designer and few months later I have been promoted to Engine harness team leader, my main responsibility is to ensure the development of the Engine harness for Projects like Logan/Duster/Clio/Captur.

In the present I am working for Lear Corp. as an EDS Engineer for JLR Projects.

Experience

EDS at Lear Corporation

March 2016 - Present (1 year 1 month)

Engine Harness Team Leader at Groupe Renault

June 2015 - March 2016 (10 months)

- Harnesses development (Catia v5, Catia v6) starting from the first design phase and ending with the entrance in the serial life of the harnesses
- Assure the link with all the harness suppliers (technical modifications and respect off all the project milestones)
- Coordinates activities for product development, validation and industrialization
- Provide technical support to designers in achieving their electrical design activities
- Propose technical solutions for product and process development
- Validate technical changes and developments
- Align the actions of team members on the company's business strategy
- With the objective of risk reduction, optimization of costs and reliability.
- Physical design Harness to vehicle installation and Design for manufacture techniques (Catia V5)
- Acquisition / verification of functional information required from the supplier, defining technical solutions and implementation of the documentation associated part-study
- Participate in VAVE meetings with suppliers

- Modifying the harness for responding to the project demands, industrialization demands, harness manufacturer demands and for optimizing the costs
- Participate in meetings with other departments to analyse changes and to find solutions
- Ensuring the development and preparation of technical documentation in all phases of major projects, from the pre-project phase, through the conceptual to the final development phase with the objective of risk reduction, optimization of costs and reliability.

Engine Harness Designer at Renault

January 2013 - May 2015 (2 years 5 months)

- Analyse and validate suppliers proposals;
- Improves concept by applying different methodologies;
- Provides project design parts before or life series, following trade standards;
- Define functional sketch and validate them;
- 3D automotive electrical harness modelling using Catia V5 electrical module (Electrical Assembly Design, Electrical Part Design, Electrical Harness Assembly, Electrical Harness Installation, Electrical Wire Routing)
- Checking for clashes between electrical and other disciplines,
- Checking the electrical harness on the physical mock-up
- Vendor 2D drawing review;
- Gedelec (Gestion des données Techniques Electricités) data base administrator

Power Engineer at Enel

May 2011 - January 2013 (1 year 9 months)

Electrical Power stations (High and medium Voltage) refurbishment projects design:

- Interlocking diagrams,
- Setup installation details for HV Cells
- Setup installation details for MV Cells
- Vendor drawing review
- Bill of materials
- Primary circuits,
- Secondary circuits.

Electrical engineer at Celin

August 2010 - April 2011 (9 months)

At Iron Gates II, Potelu, Traianu, Tamadau, Isalnita and other 110/20/10kV CEZ power station projects I was responsabil with:

- Power & Control cables sizing
- Cable routing, wiring and terminations
- PullBoxes sizing
- Power and lighting panel schedule

- Setup installation details fo 20kV Cells
- Vendor drawing review
- Bill of materials
- One line, Schematic and Loop diagram
- Project manager for Portile de fier, Isalnita and Potelu
- Most used program is Autocad

Electrical Engineer at URS Corporation

April 2008 - July 2010 (2 years 4 months)

During South Oak Creek, QuatarGas and other URS projects I was responsible:

- PDS EERaceway cable trays, duct banks, conduits and equipments modeling
- PDS Drawing Extraction form models in microstation drawings.
- Clash identification with SmartPlant program between trays and supports, trays and piping, trays and structures, and propose to other departments solution to fix the clashes
- Bill of materials from PDS models
- Grounding, Raceway and Cable Tray layouts, Mcc One-Lines
- Exposed conduits sketch
- One line, Schematic and Loop diagram
- Power and lighting panel schedule
- Power & Control cables, cable trays and conduits sizing
- Vendor drawing review
- Cable routing, wiring and terminations
- Project Database creation for electrical parts
- Most used programs were Microstation and PDS

Projects

South Oak Crek Power Plant

August 2008 to April 2010

Members:Gheorghe Despina, MARIAN ION, Iulia P#una (Popusoi)

Oak Creek Power Plant, also known as South Oak Creek, is a base load, coal- and natural gas-fired, electrical power station located on Lake Michigan in Oak Creek, Wisconsin. The plant is located on over 400 acres (1.6 km2) of land on the border of Milwaukee and Racine counties. As of 2008, the plant was in the process of a billion dollar expansion. In 2009, it was listed as the third largest generating station in Wisconsin with a net summer capacity of 1,135 MW.

Iron Gates II 110/20/6kV

October 2010 to March 2011

Members: Gheorghe Despina, Patrasescu Florin-Ovidiu

The Iron Gate II Hydroelectric Power Station (Romanian: Por#ile de Fier I, Serbian: ##### I, #erdap I) is the largest dam on the Danube river and one of the largest hydro power plants in Europe. It is located on the Iron Gate gorge, between Romania and Serbia.

Isalnita

Members: Gheorghe Despina, Patrasescu Florin-Ovidiu

The I#alni#a Power Station is a large thermal power plant located in I#alni#a, Dolj County having 8 generation groups, 3 of 50 MW, 1 of 55 MW, 2 of 100 MW and 2 groups of 315 MW having a total electricity generation capacity of 1,035 MW.

Chimcomplex Power Station

Members: Gheorghe Despina

110kV lines protection with Siemens Relay 7SJ, and Transformars protection with Siemens Realy 7UT

Traianu 110/20kV

Members:Gheorghe Despina

CEZ Power Station

Courses

Power Engineer

Enel

ANRE - National Authority for Energy Regulatory SAP

Electrical Engineer

URS Corporation Autocad

PDS

SmartPland Review

Languages

English (Professional working proficiency)

French (Elementary proficiency)
Italian (Elementary proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

Electrical Engineering Microstation PDS AutoCAD **Microsoft Office**

Good ability to adapt to multicultural environments

Team Leadership

Electrical

Power Plants

Electricians

Oil/Gas

Project Engineering

Power Engineering

Electric Power

Substation

High Voltage

Electrical Design

Power Distribution

Power Systems

Engineering Design

Engineering

MicroStation

Oil & Gas

Project Management

CAD

Automotive

Automation

CATIA

Project Planning

Energy

Electrical Wiring

Manufacturing

Automotive Engineering

Teamcenter

Education

Politehnic University Bucharest

Engineer, Electrical, 2003 - 2008

Gheorghe Despina

EDS Engineer

gigidespina@gmail.com



Contact Gheorghe on LinkedIn